Ashok K.R Frontend Developer

My website - www.ashok.live

Email - ashobiz@gmail.com

Phone - +91-9600869563

LinkedIn - www.linkedin.com/in/ashobiz/

Creative **Frontend Developer (React.js & JavaScript)** with **9.10 years** of Experience in building amazing web apps. Relevant experience in React.js is **2.10 years**.

Skills: React.js, Javascript, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Git GUI, Jest, React testing library.

Other skills: Typescript, Node.js, jQuery, express.js, MongoDB, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Illustrator.

Work Experience:

Dec, 2020 - 12, Nov, 2021: Photon Infotech, Bangalore

Currently, working as a Senior Software Engineer in Photon. I use **React.js**, **Redux**, **Javascript**, **HTML5**, **CSS3** to build UI and implement REST API based on the given requirement. Along with the said technologies, I also used many libraries namely, hook form, react vix, redux thunk, react tabs, jspdf, jest & react testing library.

Achievement in Photon:

I built a React Component which generates PDF based on the HTML, on the fly. There aren't many React libraries which generate PDF, so I built a custom library.

Project in Photon: Wound Management System

In Photon, I worked in a wound management system project for a US client. It is an enterprise application. It is a complete wound & patient management system which allows users to create & manage patients, customer, wound records, products, etc., It also has machine learning & AI functionality which analyzes the uploaded wound image. Backend is .Net. It also has Android and iOS App.

My role:

- Attend grooming calls with the client and gather requirements.
- Understand the given user story and UI designs.
- Build UI using React, Redux, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, etc.,
- Connect UI with API.
- Write unit test cases for the UI.
- Make use of devops tools like GIT, Azure CI/CD to provide builds.
- Fix bugs raised by the QA team.
- Create a widget specification document for each sprint.
- Regular calls with other team members to solve issues and provide support.

2016 - 2020: Freelance Frontend Developer

As Javascript technologies like Angular & React became very popular, I added React to my skill set. Over the years, I built many web apps using **React.js**, **Javascript**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **Sass**.

Project: Clinic management system

While freelancing, I built a clinic management system for a doctor in the USA. It was built using **React**, **HTML**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap**. The backend in Node.js. It allow doctor/nurse to create/manage patients, medical records, search records, manage nurses, etc., It also has login/registration page, reminder functionality which sends email to patient about upcoming appointments, export patient records functionality, reporting dashboard, etc.,

2012 - 2016: Freelance Web Designer

I started my career as a freelance web designer. Initially I worked part time while doing my Engineering. After graduation, I became a full time freelancer. I design websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap and LESS. I am one of the early adopters of Responsive web designing and Bootstrap.

Here are some of the works:

www.backyardbrains.com

<u>ashobiz-cakefactory.netlify.app</u>

www.sarahpayne.co.uk

www.netekspert.com

ashobiz-brave.netlify.app

ashobiz-flatmania.netlify.app

nas02.netstring.de/project/zeewolde

Achievements:

- Solved many coding problems in FireCode.io and LeetCode. Currently I am a Level 4
 programmer in FireCode.io.
- I had my own web designing company between 2014 to 2016. I lead a team of two people in my company.
- I attended many web designing contests while doing my Engineering and won many prizes.

Educational qualification:

B.Tech (Information Technology) - Score **70.88%**

2006 to 2011

K.L.N. College of Engineering, Madurai.

Thanks for reading,

Ashok.K.R